Cool. We have that address here. Else if we're not on a local network,
酷~ 我们这里已经有地址了 `else` 如果我们没有在本地网络上的话
the VRF v2 coordinator address is simply going to be derived from our network config.
`vrfCoordinatorV2Address` 就是很简单的源于我们的 "networkConfig"
So let's import the network config as well from our helper Hardhead config
所以让我们把 `networkConfig` 也从 "helper-hardhat-config" 中导入进来
and we'll say else VRF coordinator v2 address equals network config of our chain ID.
并且执行 `else `
Let's which actually sorry, we do need the chain ID
不好意思，我们还没有创建 "chainId"
cons chain ID equals network dot config dot chain ID,
`const chainId = network.config.chainId`
chain ID of VR coordinator V to
我们需要的是 "vrfCoordinatorV2" 的 "chainId"
chain ID. You're a coordinator v2.
`[chainId]["vrfCoordinatorV2"]`
Alright, perfect. We've got the setup to work with our VRF coordinator v2 address.
非常完美，我们已经配置好了涉及 `vrfCoordinatorV2Address` 的部分
What else do we need from our raffle?
我们还需要为我们的 "Raffle" 做点什么呢？
Well, we need an entrance fee,
嗯，我们还需要一个 "entranceFee"
we probably want to change the entrance fee depending on what chain we're on,
我们希望根据我们所在链的不同而改变 "entranceFee"
we're on a more expensive chain, we might want to make this higher than others.
如果我们位于一条比较贵的链上，那我们可能就希望这个数值比较大
So let's go ahead back to our helper Hardhead config and make an entrance fee based off of the blockchain,
所以让我们回到 "helper-hardhat-config" 并创建一个基于区块链的 "entranceFee"
so for NP, maybe we want to make it 0.01 eath.
对于 Rinkeby 我们可能想设置为 0.01 以太
So we could say ethers dot utils, parse ether of 0.01.
所以我们执行 `ethers.utils.parseEther("0.01")`
And once again, thank you VS code for automatically dropping that in for me.
再一次，感谢 VS Code 帮我自动添加了这些
And we're also going to want an entrance fee for our heart app,
我们同样需要给我们的 hardhat 也提供一个 "entranceFee"
we can also set a default in here, but let's just be a little more explicit.
我们也可以将其设置为默认，不过我们还是让它更明确一些吧
So we'll say 31337. The name of this is Art app,
所以我们写下 `31337: `
we don't need to give it a veneer of coordinator v2 address
我们并不需要为其提供 "vrfCoordinatorV2Address"
because we're going to deploy a mock.
因为我们要为其部署一个 "mock"
But we do want an entrance fee.
但我们希望给它一个 "entranceFee"
And let's just give it the exact same entrance fee here.
让我们给他一个完全相同的 "entranceFee" 吧
So we'll say ethers dot utils dot parse ether 0.01 E.
也就是 `ethers.utils.parseEther("0.01")`
Alright, great. So on our deploy here, we can just say const entrance fee equals network config. Chain ID of entrance fee.
好的，现在在我们的部署脚本这里，我们可以执行 `const entranceFee = networkConfig[chainId][entranceFee]`
Let's start populating our arcs here.
让我们开始填充这里的 "args"
So the first one is going to be your Fe two coordinator address. Next one is going to be our entrance fee.
第一个是你的 `vrfCoordinatorV2Address`，下一个是我们的 `entranceFee`
Got it? Got it. Now we need our gas lane.
懂了吧？应该都懂了，现在来处理我们的 "gasLane"
On Rigby and other networks, there are different gas lanes that we can choose from,
在 Rinkeby 或是其它网络上，它们都有不同的 "gasLane" 供我们选择
let's grab the only gas Lane from Rinckey, the 30, gray key hash,
让我们获取 Rinkeby 上唯一的 "gasLane"，"30 gwei Key Hash"
let's drop this, of course into our network config as gasoline, pop it in here,
获取它，并将其放入我们的 "networkConfig"，就放在这里 `gasLane`
we're hard hat, our mock actually doesn't care what gas line we're working on,
至于 hardhat，我们的 "mock" 实际上并不在乎我们用的是什么 "gasLane"
because we're going to be mocking the gasoline anyways.
因为无论是什么 gasLane 最终都是它模拟的
So we can just say gas lane, we can just go ahead and use the same one
所以我们可以直接写 `gasLane` 并使用和上面相同的一个
or really anything here, it doesn't really matter.
或者是任何一个，这并不重要
Now here we'll say const, gasoline equals network config. Chain ID, gasoline,
现在我们可以写 `const gasLane = networkConfig[chainId]["gasLane"]`
and we'll grab the gas lane. And we'll stick it into our argument array,
获取 "gasLane" 并把它粘贴进我们的 "args" 数组
we've got this one, we've got this one, we've got this one.
我们搞定了这个，而且搞定了这个，还搞定了这个
Now it's time for the subscription ID.
现在轮到 "subscriptionId" 了
Now if you haven't run through docstoc chain link for the chain link VRF,
如果你还没有通过 "docs.chain.link" 运行过 "Chainlink VRF"
I highly recommend you do so so that you can understand what this subscription ID is
那我强烈推荐你去试一下，这样你才能理解 "subscriptionID" 是什么
we know that we can actually make a subscription ID using that front end using that website VRF dot chain dot link,
我们知道，我们可以使用前端网址 "vrf.chain.link" 来创建一个 "subscriptionId"
which is great and all but what if we're on all local chains,
这很好，但如果我们是在本地链上呢？
we can get a subscription ID no problem in here.
我们可以毫无障碍的从这里获取到 "subscriptionId"
But it's a little bit harder on a local network.
但在本地网络上这就有点难了
Now I'm actually going to teach you how to create and fund subscription it is completely programmatically.
现在我会教你如何完全程序化地创建和资助一个订阅
So you don't even need to use the UI if you don't want to.
这样的话，如果你不想，甚至可以不使用 UI
However, for the purpose of this course, we're still going to use the user interface,
然而，为了达到这门课的目的，我们仍然会使用用户界面
we're still going to use that website for us to get our own subscription IDs.
仍然会使用网站来获取我们的 "subscriptionId"
But you could 100% automate the process of creating a subscription ID and funding a subscription ID.
但你完全可以自动化创建和资助 "subscriptionId" 的过程
Because when you create and fund subscription IDs,
因为当你创建和资助 "subscriptionId" 时
you're just calling create subscription and fund subscription on that smart contract.
你只是调用智能合约上的创建订阅和资助订阅罢了
So on our development chain, we have our V RF coordinator v2 Mock,
在开发链上，我们有这个 "vrfCoordinatorV2Mock"
and what we're going to do and on our development chain, we're going to create that subscription.
接下来我们要做的是，在开发链上创建订阅
So we're gonna say const, transaction, response equals await VRF coordinator v2 Mock dot create sub scription.
我们要这么写 `const transactionResponse = await vrfCoordinatorV2Mock.createSubscription()`
And then we'll run const transaction receipt equals weight trends action response, dot Wait,
然后运行 `const transactionReceipt = await transactionResponse.wait()`
wait one block confirmation.
等待一个区块确认
And inside this transaction receipt, there's actually an event that's emitted
在这个 "transactionReceipt" 的内部，实际上有一个事件
with our subscription that we can get
它会被我们获取的订阅触发
this is another place where emitting events is incredibly helpful.
这是另一处证明事件触发很有用的地方
So in fact, if we open back up a Vera v2 coordinator mark, and we look for create subscription,
事实上，如果我们回去打开 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock" 检索 "createSubscription"
we see we emit subscription created with the subscription ID,
就会看到 "emit SubscriptionCreated()" 参数就是 "subscriptionId"
we can actually get this event emitted from our transaction receipt.
我们可以从 "transactionReceipt" 中获取到这个被触发的 "event"
Now to assign it, let's go ahead and create a sub subscription ID up here.
现在来分配一下，在这里创建一个 `subscriptionId`
And then we'll say subscription ID equals transaction receipt that events of zero dot args dot sub ID.
然后下面是 `subscriptionId = transactionReceipt.events[0].args.subId`
And again, be sure to watch that events video
再提醒一下，如果你想深入了解 "event" 是如何在 Hardhat 中生效的
if you want to learn more about how to work with events in hardware.
那么一定要去看一下那个关于 "event" 的视频
Now that we have a subscription, we need to fund the subscription
现在我们有了一个订阅，我们还需要资助这个订阅
on a real network, you'd need the link token to actually fund the subscription.
在真实网络上，你还需要有 Link 代币才能真正资助这个订阅
The current iteration of the mock allows you to fund a subscription without the link token.
当前的 "mock" 版本允许你在没有 Link 代币的情况下资助订阅
So what we can do is we can just run a wait your F corps inator Mark,
所以我们要做的就是运行 `await vrfCoordinatorMock`
if coordinator B to Mach dot fund subscription, and we'll give it the subscription ID
应该是 `vrfCoordinatorV2Mock.fundSubscription(subscriptionId)`
and we'll need to do some fundamental
并提供相应的资助金额
this, we can just create some variable,
我们可以创建一些变量
we'll say const VRF, subscription fund amount equals ethers dot utils, dot parse ether, of, we'll say 30
`const VRF_SUB_FUND_AMOUNT = ethers.utils.parseEther("30")`
VRF subscription, fundament. We'll just paste that down here.
"VRF_SUB_FUND_AMOUNT" 直接粘贴到下面这里
We could do this as well for a real test net or live networks.
我们可以对实际的测试网络或真实网络做同样的操作
But just so that we become familiar with the user interface, we're not going to do a test net programmatically.
但为了让我们熟悉用户界面，我们就不在测试网上进行程序化操作了
And for a test net, we're just going to use exactly what we've been doing so far.
对测试网来说，我们要使用和之前完全相同的做法
Or we can put a subscription ID and our helper config.
或者我们可以把 "subscriptionId" 放进我们的 "helper-config" 中
So we'll say subscription ID, we'll put something in here right now,
所以我们写 `subscriptionId` 并在这里放上一些内容
we'll just leave it as zero. But later on, when we actually create a subscription, we'll update our subscription ID.
目前我们设置为 0，但等我们创建完订阅之后，就会把它更新为我们的 "subscriptionId"
And so we'll say subscription ID equals network config. Change ID of subscription ID.
接着我们写 `subscriptionId = networkConfig[chainId]["subscriptionId"]`
Perfect.
完美!
Now we can add this to our arguments array.
现在我们可以把它添加进我们的 "args" 数组
What else do we need
我们还需要些什么？
subscription ID, we need a callback gas limit
"subscriptionId" 下面是 "callbackGasLimit"
or callback, gas limit is going to vary network to network.
"callbackGasLimit" 会随着网络的变化而变化
So once again, we're gonna go into our helper configure callback gas limit.
所以再一次回到我们的 "helper-config" 写下 `callbackGasLimit`
And for us, we'll set a pretty high limit of 500,000 gas.
我们要设置一个比较大的限制，500,000 gas
So we'll say call a gas limit of 5.123 500,000. Gas.
所以我们说 `callbackGasLimit: "500000"` 也就是 500,000 gas
And for hard hat, we'll do the same thing.
对 hardhat 来说，我们要做的事情相同
So we can say const, callback, gas limit equals network config, chain ID, callback, gas limit,
现在我们就可以写 `const callbackGasLimit = networkConfig[chainId]["callbackGasLimit"]`
grab this, put it into our argument array.
获取它，并且放到我们的 "args" 数组中
What else do we need? All we need now is the interval.
我们还需要些什么？现在轮到 "interval" 了
So we can change this network to network as well.
我们同样可以让它随着网络的变化而变化
Rigby will say, interval will ever just be 30 seconds for both hard hat and for Rigby.
对 Rinkeby 来说 `interval`，然后直接把 Rinkeby 和 hardhat 都设置为 `30` 秒
So we'll do the same thing here.
接下来要做的事情还是一样
Say const. Interval equals network config. Chain ID, interval,
`const intercal = networkConfig[chainId]["interval"]`
and we'll grab this, pop it in the end of our array.
然后我们获取它，并把它放进我们数组的末尾处
All right, awesome.
干得好，非常好
Now we have an argument array and drop it right in here
现在我们有了参数数组，并且把它放进了这里
and perfect. Everything in our constructor for our raffle contract.
完美，这就是我们 "Raffle" 合约的构造函数所需要的一切
Great. This is looking fantastic.
很好，看起来好极了
We've got wait confirmations we got logging arguments Deployer.
我们有了 "waitConfirmations" 还有 "log, args, deployer"
Okay, well, what next?
好的，下一个是什么？
Well, let's go ahead and add that verification piece.
嗯，让我们继续，添加验证环节
So once again, create a new folder utils, new file verify.js.
再次新建文件夹 `utils`，新建文件 `verify.js`
We can either copy paste this from our last project,
我们可以直接从上一个项目中复制粘贴
or we can grab this from the GitHub repo associated with this course,
或是从课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中获取
once we have our verify script in here,
一旦有了验证脚本之后
we're going to import it by saying const. Verify equals require dot dot slash helper Hardhead config.
我们就把它导入进来 `const  = require("../helper-hardhat-config")`
And then we can add that same bit of code down here to verify our contract,
然后我们可以在下面添加相同的代码来验证我们的合约
we'll say if we're not on a development chain.
我们写 `if()` 如果我们不在开发链上
And we have process studying v dot ether scan API key,
并且我们还拥有 `process.env.ETHERSCAN_API_KEY` 的话
then we're going to log verifying dot dot
就执行 `log("Verifying...")`
and then await verify raffle dot address and the arcs.
然后是 `await verify(raffle.address, args)`
Now we'll just do a log of a whole bunch of hyphens say that this script is done
再执行 `log()` 里面是一堆连字符，表明这个脚本已经完成了
module dot exports dot tags equals say this will be all and raffle.
`module.exports.tags = ["all", "raffle"]`
All right, so let's test this out.
好的，让我们来测试一下它
We'll do hardhat deploy, or yarn, hard hat deploy
我们执行 `hh deploy` 或是 `yarn hardhat deploy`
and see if this script works correctly.
看一下这个脚本是否能正确运行
Looks like we ran into an error network config not defined.
看起来我们运行出了一个错误 "netwrokConfig is not defined"
（“netwrokConfig 未被定义”）
So let's spell this right. Network config.
让我们把它拼对 `networkConfig`
There we go. And that looks much better. Let's try this again.
好的，这样看起来好多了，再试一次
It looks like our deploy scripts are working well.
看起来我们的部署脚本运行良好
local networks protected, deploying mocks
"Local network detected! Deploying mocks..."
（检测到本地网络！正在部署 mocks）
deployed VRF coordinator v2 Mock
'deploying "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock"'
（正在部署 "VRFCoordinatorV2Mock"）
mocks deployed
"Mocks Deployed"
（Mocks 部署完成）
and then we went ahead and deployed our raffle.
接着我们继续部署完了我们的 "Raffle"
Awesome, this is massive.
太棒了，简直是巨大的进展